taser.com 2016-03-15

# Legal Information

## Overview

TASER International (“TASER”) knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and TASER takes your privacy seriously. TASER created this Privacy Policy Statement (“Statement”) in order to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

## Privacy Policy Coverage

This Statement covers TASER’s collection of personal information that TASER gathers when you are on TASER International websites. It does not apply to information collected and stored by a means other than these websites or practices of third parties that TASER does not own or control, or to individuals that TASER does not employ or manage. By accessing the TASER International websites, you are accepting the practices outlined in this Statement.

Access to information about customers collected from the TASER International websites is restricted to TASER and third parties that need access to customer information in order to provide TASER operational or other support services, TASER product information or product, service or upgrade offers, or as may be required by law. TASER does not distribute, sell or rent any personal information collected via its websites. This is also true for personal information (email address, postal address, etc.) sent to the websites’ email addresses. TASER does not send unsolicited emails to users of its sites. The transmission of personal information entered via the sites’ forms is protected by security features.

## TASER’s Personal Information Collection and Purpose

TASER’s primary goal in collecting information is to provide you with a friendly, customized, and efficient experience. TASER takes reasonable precautions to protect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction of personal information. We collect the following types of information from our customers:

### (A) Information You Provide to Us

TASER collects identifying information when you use the TASER International websites, and when you enter promotions or contests. For example, we may require customers who register to use the TASER International websites to give us the following personal information: their name, Company name, address, phone number, and e-mail address, and financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the identity of users within the organization that will be using the TASER International websites. When you initially express interest in obtaining additional information about the TASER International websites, or when you register on the TASER International websites, we may also ask for additional types of personal information, such as title, department name, fax number, or additional company or agency information. We may also request demographic information and unique identifiers in order to provide you with a more personalized experience or verify your passwords. All financial and billing information that we collect from you is used for the purposes of checking your qualifications as a prospective customer and billing you for purchases. TASER may use a third-party intermediary to manage the credit card and billing processing. This intermediary is solely a link in the distribution chain, and is not permitted to store, retain, or use the information provided, except for the sole purpose of credit card and billing processing.

If you are a registered user of the TASER International websites, please note that some information about you may remain in our records.

### (B) Automatic Information

TASER receives and stores certain types of information whenever you interact with us via TASER International websites. TASER automatically receives and records certain "traffic data" on our server logs including your IP address, TASER cookie information, the page you requested, and your communications and interactions with other site users. TASER uses this traffic data to help diagnose problems with its server, analyze trends and administer the TASER International websites.

TASER automatically collects usage information, such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to our websites and use of components of our websites. TASER may use this information to provide research, advice and information, including, without limitation, for benchmarking purposes (e.g. we may publish an industry white paper that uses data collected through the use of our TASER International websites). This data is only used in the aggregate. This type of collective data also enables us to figure out how often customers use parts of the TASER International websites so we can make the websites appealing to as many customers as possible. In addition, we may provide statistical information to our partners about how our customers, collectively, use the TASER International websites. We may share this type of statistical data so that our partners also understand how often people use areas of our TASER International websites, so that they, too, may provide you with an optimal experience. We also collect and use information for internal purposes.

Many companies offer programs that help you to visit web sites anonymously. While TASER will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience if we cannot recognize you, we want you to be aware that these programs are available.

### (C) Email Communications

TASER may receive a confirmation when you open an e-mail from TASER if your computer supports this type of program, in order to help us make e-mails more interesting and helpful. TASER may also send out emails with information regarding TASER including promotions and events. Customers may opt out of receiving such emails by selecting the “unsubscribe” link in the TASER email or by visiting TASER’s unsubscribe webpage.

## Information From Other Sources

For purposes such as improving personalization of the TASER International websites, TASER may receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information.

## What About Cookies

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that TASER transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our site are visited and by how many people. TASER employs cookies in order for its server to recognize a return visitor as a unique user. Cookies are used to personalize the content you view on our websites. The cookies placed by the TASER server are readable only by TASER, and cookies cannot access, read or modify any other data on a computer.

The "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. TASER strongly recommends that you leave the cookies activated because cookies enable you to take advantage of some of TASER’s most attractive features. To view more information regarding cookie settings please visit:

## Google Analytics Demographic and Interest Reporting

TASER receives Demographic and Interest Reports from Google, which include aggregated, non-personally identifiable information about our website traffic regarding visitors’ age, gender, and interests. The reports let TASER see how many of our users visit over a date range, who those users are, and how their behavior varies by attribute (e.g., male vs. female). Information regarding these reports is derived by Google from the DoubleClick third-party cookies. This information will not be used for any purpose other than those set out in this Statement.

## Google Adwords Remarketing

TASER has implemented Remarketing with Google Analytics to help personalize its advertising efforts online. Such analytics allow third party vendors, including Google, to show personalized ads on sites across the internet. TASER and third party vendors, including Google, use first and third party cookies together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on a visitor’s past visits on any TASER International website. In other words, AdWords remarketing will display relevant ads tailored to you based on what parts of the TASER International websites you have viewed, by placing a cookie on your machine. This cookie does not in any way identify you or give access to your computer. Google AdWords Remarketing allows us to tailor our marketing to better suit your needs and deliver a more personalized experience by only displaying ads that are relevant to your specific interests.

## Access To and Accuracy of Personal Information Collected By Google Analytics

Google Analytics gathers information based on an individual user’s activities on Google websites and other websites within their network. Google then determines the age, gender, and interests of the user. In order to review and edit this personal information please visit Google's [ads settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

## Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-On

In order to prevent data collected by Google Analytics, users can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. Please visit [this support article](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881) to disable Google Analytics. It is important to remember that that many of Google’s services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

## DoubleClick Third Party Cookie and Adwords Remarketing Opt-Out

DoubleClick uses cookies to improve advertising. Some common applications are to target advertising based on what’s relevant to a user, to improve reporting on campaign performance, and to avoid showing ads the user has already seen. DoubleClick sends a cookie to the browser after any impression, click, or other activity that results in a call to the DoubleClick server. If the browser accepts the cookie, the cookie is stored on the browser. In order to opt out of these DoubleClick interest-based ads and Google Adwords on either Google and/or across the web please visit Google's [ad settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

## Information Sharing

Information about TASER customers is an integral part of our business. TASER neither rents nor sells your personal information to anyone except as described in this Statement. We share your personal information only with entities that are controlled or controlled by or under common control of TASER, and as described below:

### (A) Affiliated Businesses TASER Does Not Control

TASER is affiliated or partnered with a variety of businesses and work closely with them. In certain situations, these businesses operate within the TASER International websites. In other situations, TASER markets or sells products or services jointly with affiliated businesses. If TASER intends to disclose information externally, TASER will give you the opportunity to decline to supply customer information or to opt out of such sharing.

### (B) Agents

TASER employs other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and may need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you. Examples may include removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. TASER may also provide your personal information to agents who will use it to verify aggregate usage data that we provide to our partners. In all cases where we share your information with such agents, we explicitly require the agent to acknowledge and adhere to TASER's Privacy Policy requirements. Additionally, when TASER wishes to transfer this information to a third party acting as an agent, it will only do so if the third party agent enters into a written Non-Disclosure Agreement.

### (C) Promotional Offers

TASER may send offers to certain customers on behalf of other businesses with whom TASER has a partnership. However, when TASER does so, TASER does not give the other business your name and address. If you are a user of the TASER International websites and do not wish to receive these offers, please [request to unsubscribe](http://info.taser.com/UnsubscribePage.html).

### (D) With Your Consent

Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your personal information may be shared with third parties.

Except as describes in this Statement, TASER will not share the personal information you provide to TASER with non-TASER third parties without your permission, unless to: (i) respond to duly authorized information requests of police and governmental authorities; (ii) comply with any law, regulation, subpoena, or court order; (iii) investigate and help prevent security threats, fraud, or other malicious activity; (iv) enforce/protect the rights and properties of TASER or its subsidiaries; or (v) protect the rights of personal safety of TASER employees and third parties on or using TASER International websites.

## User Information is Secure

All customer information collected and stored by TASER is maintained in a secure corporate data center and/or otherwise subject to best practices access protection. Only employees who need customer information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative) are granted access to it. All of our employees are kept up to date on our privacy and security practices.

## Access To and Accuracy of Your Information

TASER strives to keep your personal information accurately recorded. TASER has implemented technology, management processes and policies to help maintain data accurately. TASER provides individuals with reasonable access to personal information that they provide to TASER and the reasonable ability to review and correct it or ask for anonymization, blockage, or deletion, as applicable. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as requiring a password and user ID, before granting access to your data. To change your personal information that you directly provided to TASER you can contact us on TASER’s [support webpage](http://www.taser.com/support/contact-us).

If you feel that any personal information about you that has been collected and stored by TASER might be wrong, or you would like for us to correct, amend or remove your information from our systems, please [notify us](http://www.taser.com/support/contact-us) so that we may correct or delete the information.

## User Choices

As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose information, even though it may be needed to make a purchase or take advantage of certain TASER International website features.

You are able to add or update certain information as described in the "Access to and Accuracy of your Information" section above. When you update information, however, we may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records.

As explained earlier, the "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. You can find information on popular browsers and how to adjust your cookie preference at the following websites [for Internet Explorer](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies) and [for Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences). Please note, however, that if you do not enable cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of some of our attractive features.

## Children's Online Privacy Protection Act

TASER takes seriously its obligations under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act concerning the collection of personal information from individuals under the age of thirteen (13). The TASER International websites are not directed at children, as TASER requests that children under the age of 13 not provide personal information through the TASER International websites.

## Third Party Sites

The TASER International websites may permit you to link to other websites on the Internet, and other websites may contain links to the TASER International websites. These other websites are not under TASER control, and such links do not constitute an endorsement by TASER of those other websites or the services offered through them. The privacy and security practices of websites linked to or from the TASER International websites are not covered by this Statement, and TASER is not responsible for the privacy or security practices or the content of these websites.

TASER may also provide social media features that enable you to share information with your social networks and to interact with TASER on various social media sites. Your use of these features may result in the collection or sharing of information about you, depending on the feature. TASER encourages you to review the privacy policies and settings on the social media sites with which you interact to make sure you understand the information that may be collected, used and shared by those sites.

## Keeping Personal Information Secure

TASER takes seriously the trust you place in us. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, TASER utilizes reasonable and appropriate physical, technical, and administrative procedures to safeguard the information we collect. TASER retains data only as required or permitted by local law and while it has a legitimate business purpose.

## Conditions of Use

If you decide to visit TASER International websites, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy, arbitration of disputes, and Arizona law.

TASER commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. If you have any questions or concerns regarding your personal information or would like to contact our offices to report a complaint please [contact us](http://www.taser.com/support/contact-us).

## Policy Changes

TASER reserves the right to amend the Privacy Policy Statement at any time with or without notice. Please check back frequently in the event of changes.

Your use of any of the TASER International websites constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy.

## Questions or Concerns

If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy at TASER International websites, please contact us at contact us. Your privacy is important to us and we will make every effort to resolve your concerns.

Revised March 6, 2015

TASER® and © are registered trademarks of TASER International, Inc. ©2015 TASER International, Inc. All rights reserved.
